本字幕由厦门大学张统一亲手制作
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：张统一   时间轴：张统一   翻译：张统一   校对：张统一
谨以此片
祝各位朋友在新的一年里
心想事成
暮光之城 破晓 （下）
克里斯汀·斯图尔特
罗伯特·帕丁森
泰勒·劳特纳
# Where I come from #
我来的地方
# You say things will be well and fun #
你说一切都会很好玩
# Though the world around you is crumbling #
# 虽然你的世界在崩塌 #
# and the truth bleak as a bee stay close believe #
# 事实很残酷 但你要相信自己 #
# Though things are not what they seem #
# 虽然事情不是像他们看起来的那样 #
# I won't let them destroy these dreams #
# 但我不会让他们毁了这些梦 #
# They are just things #
# 那只是一些 #
# Silly little things #
# 很傻很天真的东西 #
So beautiful.
真美
We're the same temperature now.
我们现在体温一样了
Hey, Bella,
嘿 贝拉
you're a lot stronger than I am right now.
你现在可比我强壮多了
It's your turn not to break me.
轮到你轻手轻脚了
I love you.
我爱你
Renesmee.
蕾埃斯梅
She's incredible.
她无与伦比
Where is she? I have to see her.
她在哪儿? 我得见她
Wait. Wait.
不急 不急
You need to get your thirst under control.
你得控制好对人血的饥渴
Yeah, you'll need to hunt.
你得捕猎
Close your eyes.
闭上眼
What do you hear?
听到了什么?
Bella, don't!
贝拉 别
Bella, stop!
贝拉 停下
I'm sorry, I didn't realize there'd be people this far from the trails.
我错了 我没想到离道路这么远还有人类出没
I have to get outta here.
我得离开这儿
Okay, I can help you.
好 我来帮你
Or not.
看来不用
Well, I'm amazed.
你让我大开眼界
You ran away from human blood mid-hunt.
你竟然能在狩猎时主动远离人血
Even mature vampires have problems with that.
这连成熟的吸血鬼都很难做到
You're still here.
你还在这儿
So are you.
你不也一样
I didn't expect you to seem so
没想到你看起来这么像
you.
原来的样子
Except for the creepy eyes.
除了那双吓人的眼睛
I would keep my distance for now.
我会和你保持距离
It's safer for the baby to see how you do with me first.
先看看你对我的反应如何 对孩子来说更安全
Since when do you care about Renesmee?
你何时开始关心蕾埃斯梅起来了?
All right.
来
Take a whiff.
闻一下
Well, I can see what everyone's been talking about.
我总算明白别人一直说的了
Jake, you really do stink.
雅各布 你真心不好闻
You guys
你们
really look great together.
真的很般配
Want to come meet our daughter?
想见见咱女儿吗?
Welcome to the family.
欢迎回家
You look amazing, Bella.
你美极了 贝拉
Someone's been waiting to meet you.
有人已经恭候多时了
Rose.
洛萨丽
Beautiful.
真漂亮
What was that?
刚才那是什么?
She showed you the first memory she has of you.
她给你看了第一次见你时的记忆
Showed me? How?
给我看? 怎么做到的?
How do I hear thoughts?
我怎么洞察人心?
How does Alice see the future?
爱丽丝怎么预见未来?
She's gifted.
这是她的天赋
I've only been out for two days?
我只离开了两天吗?
Her growth rate is unprecedented.
它的生长速度惊人
All right. That's enough experimenting for one day.
好了 今天就到这儿吧
Jacob.
雅各布
She's doing great.
她表现得很好
Yeah. Let's not push it though.
没错 但也别强求
What's your problem?
你什么情况?
Oh.
哦
Do tell her, Jacob.
一定告诉她 雅各布
This should be good.
有好戏看了
Hold on a second.
先等一下
Bella.
贝拉
Look,
听好了
it's a wolf thing.
这是我们狼族的东西
What's a wolf thing?
什么狼族的东西?
Um...
呃...
You know we have no control over it.
我们没法控制
We can't choose who it happens with.
我们不能选择它发生在谁身上
And it doesn't mean what you think, Bella. I promise.
不是你想的那样 贝拉 我保证
（根据原著 贝拉以为雅各布想娶雷埃斯梅）
Take Renesmee out of the room.
把蕾埃斯梅带出去
Oh.
唉
Edward, don't touch me right now.
爱德华 现在别碰我
I don't want to hurt you.
我不想伤了你
Oh.
啊
You imprinted on my daughter?
你看上我女儿了?
It wasn't my choice!
这不是我能选择的!
She's a baby!
它还是个婴儿!
It's not like that.
不是你想的那样
You think Edward would let me live if it was?
要是这样爱德华还会让我活着吗?
I'm still debating it.
争论中
I've held her once!
我就抱过她一次
One time, Jacob!
就一次 雅各布!
And already you think that you have some moronic
你已经觉得以你们白痴狼族的方式
wolfy claim on her?
占有她了吗?
She's mine!
她是我的!
It's fine, Leah.
没事 里昂
You're gonna stay away from her.
你给我离她远点
You know I can't do that.
你明知我做不到
Stop her, Edward.
阻止他 爱德华
He said it's fine.
他说了没事儿
She's amazing, right?
她真厉害 是吗?
Do you remember how much you wanted to be around me 3 days ago?
你还记得3天前你有多想和我在一起吗?
That's gone now, right?
现在没感觉了?
Long gone.
早就没了
Because it was her.
因为从一开始是她
From the beginning it was Nessie who wanted me there.
是尼斯想和我在一块
Nessie?
尼斯?
You nicknamed my daughter after the Loch Ness monster?
你给我的女儿起了个"尼斯湖水怪"的小名?
Seth, are you okay?
赛斯 你没事吧?
Seth, I'm sorry.
赛斯 抱歉
He'll be all right.
他没事儿
Bella,
贝拉
you know me better than anyone.
你比任何人都更懂我
All I want is for Ness...
我只是想尼...
Renesmee to be safe. Happy.
蕾埃斯梅安好
Look,
你想想看
nothing ever made sense before.
之前的所有东西都不合常理
You. Me. Any of it.
你 我 一切的一切
And now I understand why.
现在我明白为什么了
This was the reason.
这就是原因
Finally.
终于回来了
My turn.
该我了
Where does she sleep?
她睡哪儿?
In my arms. Or Edward's or Esme's.
我怀里 或者爱德华和埃斯梅的怀里
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
I stopped aging three days ago.
我三天前就停止长大了
Well, we're celebrating anyway. So suck it up.
我才不管 还得庆祝 忍着吧
I still hate surprises. That hasn't changed.
我依旧讨厌惊喜 这可一点没变
You'll love this one.
你会喜欢这个惊喜的
Welcome home!
欢迎回家!
We thought you guys might like a place of your own.
我们觉得你俩会喜欢自己的小世界
What do you think?
感觉如何?
I think it's perfect.
太完美了
Go inside.
进去吧
Have fun.
好好玩
This will be Renesmee's room.
这会是蕾埃斯梅的房间
Closet.
衣柜
Wow.
哇
Alice stocked it for you.
爱丽丝替你存的
Clearly.
显然
This is our room.
这是我们的卧室
Vampires don't sleep.
吸血鬼不睡觉的
It's not intended for sleep.
不是为睡觉准备的
You really were holding back before.
你之前真是攒着劲儿啊
I'm never gonna get enough of this.
我怎么也不会满足的
We don't get tired.
我们不会累
We don't have to rest or catch our breath or eat.
不用休息喘口气或是吃东西
I mean,
我是说
how are we gonna stop?
我们怎么才能停下来啊?
Rosalie and Emmett were so bad, it took a solid decade
洛萨丽和艾美特很严重 他们不让我们靠近
before we could stand to be within five miles of them.
5英里内整整十年
I think we might be worse.
我觉得我们会更疯狂
Definitely worse.
肯定的
Wow.
哇
Done already?
已经做完了?
Where's Renesmee?
蕾埃斯梅在哪?
Blondie stole her.
那金头发偷走了
Break a lot of stuff?
弄坏很多东西吧
Emmett.
艾美特
No.
别说了
Is that Charlie?
是查理打来的?
He's been calling twice a day.
他一直是每天两个电话
He's in pretty rough shape.
他很不好过
Eventually, we'll have to tell him you didn't make it.
最后 我们总要告诉他你没活下来
He needs to mourn, Bella.
他得默哀 贝拉
Okay. We'll do it tomorrow.
好吧 我们明天告诉他
I'm gonna miss this place.
我会想念这个地方的
We'll come back. We always do.
我们会回来的 我们总能回来
Wait.
等等
Nobody said anything about leaving.
没人说过要离开啊
Once people believe Bella's dead, we can't risk anyone seeing her.
一旦人们相信了贝拉的死讯 我们不能再冒险让人看到她
So you just disappear?
所以你们就离开?
Jacob, we don't have another choice.
雅各布 我们别无选择
Hey.
嘿
You heard anything?
有贝拉消息吗?
Charlie,
查理
Bella is...
贝拉她...
Uh...
哦...
No, she's not.
不会的 她没死
No, no, no, I mean, she's fine.
不 不 我是说 她很好
She's back home and
她已经回来了
she's feeling better.
她感觉好多了
Why didn't you say so? That's great.
怎么不早说? 太好了
Wait.
等等
There's something you need to see first.
有些事情你得先了解一下
I need to see Bella.
我得去见贝拉
Look,
听好了
in order for Bella to get better, she had to
为了让贝拉变好 她不得不
change.
变化
What do you mean, "change"?
变化? 什么意思?
Here goes nothing.
下面的事情就当没发生过
What the hell are you doing?
你他妈的干嘛?
You don't live in the world you think you do.
你在的世界不是你想的那样
Jacob, put your clothes on.
雅各布 把衣服穿上
Now, this may seem strange.
接下来你看到的会比较奇怪
Really strange. But
非常奇怪 但是
stranger things happen every day.
比这还奇怪的事情每天都在发生
Trust me.
相信我
Holy shit!
我勒个去!
Look, I solved a problem.
听好了 我解决了一个问题
You were leaving.
你要走
What did you expect me to do?
你想让我怎么做
You don't realize the danger you've put him in.
你没意识到你把他置于何等险境当中了
The Volturi will kill anyone who knows about us.
沃统一家族会杀了所有知道我们存在的人
No, I didn't tell him about you. Just me.
不 我没把你的情况告诉他 只有我
I only said you were different.
我只是说你有些变化
And that we have a niece who we adopted.
我们还有了一个领养的侄子
I mean, seriously, Jake, he's not just gonna let that go.
我是认真的 雅各布 他不会轻易相信的
Did you consider the physical pain he'll put Bella through?
你考虑过查理给贝拉带来的身体上的痛苦吗?
It'll be like sticking a white hot branding iron down her throat.
这就好比把一块白热的铁块插到他的喉咙里
And that's assuming she can control her thirst.
这还是得先假定她能控制自己的饥渴
Look, Charlie's been in hell.
听好了 查理现在生不如死
And I know you'll be much happier with him in your life.
有他在你身边你会更开心的
Jacob, don't try and pretend you're doing this for anyone but yourself.
雅各布 别假装你不是为自己才这样做
Sorry you feel that way
很遗憾你那样想
because he'll be here in 10 minutes.
因为他10分钟后就回到这儿
What?
啥?
These will irritate your eyes at first.
它起初会对眼睛有些刺激
The main thing is not to move too fast.
主要是别移动太快
Try taking a seat. Crossing your legs.
试着坐下 把腿biao起来
Maybe a tad slower. Hmm.
再慢一点 一丢丢
And blink at least three times a minute.
一分钟至少眨三次眼
Good.
不错
For a cartoon character.
对于卡通人物来说
Hold your breath. It will help with the thirst.
屏住呼吸 有助于抑制饥渴
Just don't forget to move your shoulders so it looks like you're breathing.
别忘了动肩膀 这样看起来你就在呼吸
And don't sit so straight.
别坐太直
Humans don't do that.
人类做不了那么直
Okay. I got it.
好的 我知道了
Move around, blink, slouch.
移动慢 眨眼睛 驼着背
Good luck.
祝你好运
Hello, Charlie.
你好 查理
Where's Bella?
贝拉在哪儿?
Bella.
贝拉
Hi, Dad.
嗨 爸
Are you okay?
你还好吗?
Never better.
再没这么好过了
Healthy as a horse.
壮成一匹马
You don't turn into an animal, too, do you?
你不会变成怪物吧?
She wishes she was that awesome.
她倒想有那么厉害
Let's give them some privacy.
让他们单独待一会儿吧
Uh, Jake said that this...
啊 雅各布说这...
This was necessary.
这是必需的
What does that mean?
什么意思?
I really think it would be better...
我真心觉得你不知道会更好...
I wanna know what happened to you.
我想知道你怎么了
I can't tell you.
我不能告诉你
I think I deserve an explanation.
我应得一个解释
You do.
没错
But if you really need one, I can't stay here.
但是如果你真的要解释 我就不能在这儿了
Oh, come on! No!
哦 不要
No more going away!
别再走了!
Dad, you're just gonna have to trust that for whatever reason,
爸 不管什么原因 你必须得相信我
I'm all right.
我很好
I'm more than all right.
我不止很好
Can you live with that?
你能接受吗?
Can I live With that?
我能接受吗?
Well, I don't know, Bella.
我不知道 贝拉
I mean, I just watched a kid I've known his entire life
我是说 我刚刚见证了我看着长大的孩子
turn into a very large dog.
变成了一条大狗
My daughter looks like my daughter.
我女儿看起来和原来很像
But doesn't.
但不再一样了
Can you please just believe that I'll tell you anything that you need to know?
你能先相信我会告诉你所有你需要知道的事情吗?
And I don't need to know this?
我不必知道这些?
No.
不需要
Really, you don't.
真心不需要
Well...
恩...
Not gonna lose you again.
不能再失去你了
I can't.
我不能
Then you won't.
你不会的
I promise.
我保证
I missed you, Bells.
我想你 贝拉
So much.
非常想
I missed you, Dad.
我也想你 爸
Charlie.
查理
This is Renesmee.
这是蕾埃斯梅
Your niece?
你侄子?
Our daughter.
我们的女儿
Right.
对了
The adoption.
领养
Renee-semee?
蕾埃-斯梅
She's got your eyes, Bella.
她和你眼睛很像 贝拉
Need to know, I guess.
需要知道
Well done, Bella.
不错啊 贝拉
Never seen a newborn show that kind of restraint.
从没见过哪个新生儿有这么强的克制力
I'm not sure she is a newborn.
我可不觉得他是新生的
She's so tame.
她这么温顺
Emmett, don't antagonize her.
艾美特 别惹她
She's the strongest one in the house.
她是这栋房里最强壮的
Please.
得了吧
Don't hurt yourself, Emmett.
别伤着自己 艾美特
All right. On 3.
好 我数到三
1,
一
2,
二
3!
三
Did you see that?
你看到没有?
Thank you.
谢谢
My time as a human was over.
我的人类生涯结束了
But I never felt more alive.
但是我从没感到这么有活力
I was born to be a vampire.
我生来就是当吸血鬼的料
Everything was falling into place.
每件事都尘埃落定
Even the Volturi seemed to accept my new status.
就连沃统一家族也似乎接受了我的存在
Though they'd want proof eventually.
虽然他们终究是要证据的
It seemed we had only one enemy left.
看起来我们只剩一个敌人了
Time.
时光
Renesmee was growing too fast.
蕾埃斯梅长得太快了
We all worried about how long we would have with her.
我们都很担心我们能和她在一起多长时间
It just made every moment more precious.
这让每时每刻都那么珍贵
Look, a snowflake.
看 是雪花
It's beautiful.
真漂亮
Why don't you go get another one?
何不再抓一片?
Edward thinks that we'll find answers in Brazil.
爱德华认为我们会在巴西找到答案
There are tribes there that might know something.
那里的部落或许知道答案
Who was that?
那是谁?
I think that's our cousin from Denali.
我们来自德纳里的表亲
Irina!
伊琳娜!
Tanya convinced Irina to come reconcile with us.
坦尼亚说服了伊琳娜
It looks like she changed her mind.
看起来她改变主意了
Seeing Jacob must have been too much for her.
看到雅各布对他的打击一定很大
Wish I could have just spoken to her.
要是刚才能和她谈谈就好了
She's family. She'll come around.
他是亲戚 会来串门的
What a pleasant surprise.
多么美妙的惊喜
What do you want?
有何贵干?
Hmm?
恩?
I have to report a crime.
我要举报一桩罪行
The Cullens...
Cullen家族...
They've done something terrible.
他们做了件骇人听闻的坏事
Allow me, my dear.
请允许我 亲爱的
Oh, my.
噢 天啊
What is it, Alice?
怎么了 Alice
The Volturi.
沃统一家族
They're coming for us.
他们来找我们算账了
Aro, Caius, Marcus, the Guard.
阿罗 凯厄斯 马库斯 守卫都来了
And Irina.
还有伊琳娜
Honey, come here.
亲爱的 来这儿
Why?
为何?
What did Irina see in the woods?
伊琳娜在树林里看到了什么?
We were just walking.
我们在散步
Ness was catching snowflakes.
尼斯在接雪花
Of course.
果真
Irina thinks Renesmee's an Immortal Child.
伊琳娜觉得蕾埃斯梅是吸血鬼小孩儿
The Immortal Children were very beautiful.
吸血鬼孩子很漂亮
So enchanting.
很迷人
To be near them was to love them.
接近他们就会爱上他们
But their development was frozen at the age they were turned.
但是他们的生长在被转化的那一天就停止了
They couldn't be taught or restrained.
他们无法被教化我约束
A single tantrum could destroy an entire village.
发个小脾气就能毁掉整个村子
Humans heard about the devastation.
人类听说了惨剧
Stories spread.
故事传开了
The Volturi were forced to intervene.
沃统一家族被迫干预
Since the Children couldn't protect our secret,
因为小孩子不能保守秘密
they had to be destroyed.
所以他们必须被毁灭
No!
不!
Their creators grew very attached and fought to protect them.
他们的创造者很不舍 就奋起反击保护他们
Long-established covens were torn apart.
建立很久的女巫集会被解散
Countless humans slaughtered.
无数人类被屠杀
Traditions, friends,
传统 朋友
even families. Lost.
家人 都不复存在
No, no!
不 不!
- Mother!  - No!
- 妈!  - 不!
Mother!
妈!
So the Denalis' mother made an Immortal Child?
丹娜莉的妈妈创造了一个吸血鬼孩子?
Yes.
是的
And she paid the price.
她也付出了代价
Well, Renesmee's nothing like those children.
但是 蕾埃斯梅和这些孩子不一样
She was born, not bitten. She grows every single day.
她是被生出来的 不是被咬后转化的
So can't you just explain that to the Volturi?
你就不能和沃统一家族解释一下吗?
Aro has enough proof in Irina's thoughts.
阿罗在伊琳娜的想法里得到了足够的证据
So we fight.
那就打他娘的
Their offensive weapons are too powerful.
他们的防御技能太强了
No one can stand against Jane.
没人敌得过简
Alec's even worse.
阿莱克更厉害
Well, then we convince them.
那我们就说服他们
They're coming to kill us, not to talk.
他们是来杀我们的 不是来喷闲话的
No, you're right.
对
They won't listen to us.
他们不会听我们说的
But maybe others can convince them.
但其他人也许可以说服他们
Carlisle, you have friends all around the world.
卡莱尔 你的朋友遍天下
I won't ask them to fight.
我不会要求他们战斗的
Not fight. Witness.
不打仗 当证人
If enough people knew the truth,
知道事实的人数足够多
maybe we could convince the Volturi to listen.
或许就能说服沃统一家族听我们解释
We can ask this of our friends.
我们可以请朋友们当证人
At least we get to go to London again.
至少我们得再去一趟伦敦
We haven't been there in a long time.
我们已经很长时间没去过那儿了
All right. Let's get this show on the road.
好了 搭好台 唱大戏了
Alice asked me to give you that.
爱丽丝让我把这个给你
She and Jasper crossed our lands to the ocean last night.
她和贾斯伯昨晚跨过我们的领地朝大海方向去了
Carlisle?
卡莱尔?
They've left us.
他们离开了
Why?
为什么?
She didn't say.
他没说
Can I see that?
我能看看吗?
Gather as many witnesses as you can before the snow sticks to the ground.
在雪化之前集合尽可能多的证人
That's when they'll come.
那时候他们就来了
Alice's instructions were clear, but the question remained.
爱丽丝的指示很明确 但留下了问题
Why would she and Jasper leave at the moment we needed them most?
她和贾斯伯为什么要在我们最需要她们的时候离开
What did they know?
他们知道了什么?
Our search for witnesses began with a trip north to our closest relatives.
我们对证人的寻找
Edward, is everything all right?
爱德华 一切都好吗?
Why didn't you tell us you were coming?
要来怎么不提前说一声
Is it Irina?
是因为伊莲娜吗?
Have you heard from her?
你有她的消息吗?
Not directly.
没有直接消息
Why is your bride waiting in the car?
你的新娘怎么在车里等着?
And why have you brought a wolf with you?
为何带着着一匹狼?
I can smell him from here.
我在这儿就能闻到他
My family is in danger. I need your help.
我的家人有危险 我需要你们的帮助
What's happened?
怎么啦
It's hard to explain
很难解释
but I need you to be open-minded. Can you do that?
但是你们得做好心理准备 好吗?
Of course.
当然
Okay.
好
Time to meet some new people.
是时候见见新朋友了
What if they don't like me?
他们要是不喜欢我怎么办?
- They'll love you.  - They will.
- 他们会爱你的  - 对
Once they understand you.
只要他们了解你
They just haven't met anyone like you before.
他们只是之前从没见过像你一样的人
Okay.
好
The Volturi will come for all of us.
沃统一家族不会放过所有人
You get that thing out of here.
把那东西弄走
She's not what she looks like.
她不是看起来的那样
This is a crime!
这是犯罪!
Stay back!
退后
She has blood in her veins.
她血管里流淌着血
You can feel her warmth.
你可以感受到她的体温
I can feel it.
我能感觉到
I'm her biological father.
我是他的生父
- Bella is her mother.  - Impossible.
- 贝拉是他的生母  - 不可能
It's true. She was born while I was still human.
是真的 她在我还是人类的时候出生
I've never heard of such a thing.
从没听说过这种事情
She can show you, if you let her.
她能展示给你 如果你允许的话
Tanya, you owe us this much.
坦尼亚 你欠我们这么多
We're all under a death sentence because your sister didn't let us explain.
我们都因为面临死刑 只因你的妹妹不愿让我们解释
Don't be afraid.
别怕
This is how she communicates.
这是他交流的方式
It's true.
是真的
She's not immortal.
他不是永生的
I knew the rest of our family would face this fear as well.
我知道 我的其他家人也会面临这种恐惧
Fear of the unknown.
对未知的恐惧
Fear of the Volturi.
对沃统一的恐惧
Amun, please!
阿木 求你了!
I cannot help you, Carlisle.
我帮不了你 卡莱尔
I wouldn't ask if it weren't urgent.
要不紧急我就不问了
You must go.
你必须走
I'd like to hear about it.
我想听听
I never get to meet any of Amun's friends.
我从没见过阿木的朋友
He likes to keep me hidden.
他喜欢藏着我
I can't imagine why.
难以想象为什么
- Carlisle.  - Benjamin.
- 卡莱尔  - 本杰明
Benjamin can influence the elements.
本杰明能控制元素
And here I get super self-control.
我有很强的自控力
Who are they?
他们是谁?
Senna and Zafrina.
赛纳和扎弗里那
From the Amazon.
来自亚马逊
The arrival of Senna and Zafrina meant that our plea was being heard
赛纳和扎弗里那的到来意味着我们的请求已经被
in even the most remote corners of the world
世界最偏远的角落听到了
while others searched for witnesses closer to home.
其他人在离家较近的地方寻找证人
A patriot Carlisle first met on the battlefield at Yorktown
一个卡莱尔在南北战争约克镇战役遇到的爱国者
would become our most unlikely ally.
是我们最不能的战友
Shut up!
闭嘴
I hated the first British Invasion.
我讨厌第一次英国入侵（20世纪60年代中期英国摇滚和流行音乐在美国流行）
And I hate the second one even more.
更恨第二次（1982年-1986年英国音乐表演在美国流行）
Even the Beatles?
连甲壳虫也恨?
Really, Garrett?
真的吗 盖里特?
Old habits die hard.
老习惯很难改的
Carlisle needs you.
卡莱尔需要你
Sounds interesting.
有意思
Help!
救命!
But first I'd better finish my meal.
但我得先吃完饭
Help me! Help!
救命! 救命!
Each of them was won over.
他们都被争取了过来
Each was made to see.
每个人都了解了
Carlisle convinced his Irish friends to make the journey to Forks.
卡莱尔说服了他的爱尔兰朋友来福克斯
Although we were grateful for their help,
我们虽然感激他们的帮助
their thirst for human blood complicated the situation.
但他们对人血的饥渴复杂了局势
The nomads Rosalie and Emmett sent were even more unpredictable.
洛萨丽和艾美特带来的游牧民更难以预料
Especially Peter
尤其是皮特
who had fought alongside Jasper as a newborn.
他和贾斯伯在新生时并肩战斗过
Lotta red eyes around here.
这附近好多红眼吸血鬼啊（lotta：a lot of 的缩写）
They agreed not to hunt in the area.
他们同意不在这里捕猎
But they'll feed somewhere.
但他们总得找个地方吃东西
As more vampires set foot in their territory,
随着越来越多的吸血鬼踏入他们的领地
more Quileutes turned.
更多的奎鲁特人转化了
Their nature compelling them to join the pack.
他们的天性驱使他们加入族群
Hey, easy there. Hey!
嘿 放轻松!
It's all right.
没事儿
You're gonna be okay.
你会没事的
Finally, Carlisle and Esme returned with our last witness.
最后卡莱尔和埃斯梅带着我们最后的证人回来了
- How many came?  - Eighteen.
- 一共来了多少人?  - 十八个
You have some good friends.
你有一群好朋友
And Alice?
爱丽丝呢?
We'll all be on Aro's list now.
我们都上了阿罗的黑名单了
Centuries on the run. That's what you've brought me.
几个世纪的逃亡 这就是你给我带来的
Some friend, Carlisle.
为了个朋友 卡莱尔
Alistair, come meet everyone.
阿里斯蒂亚 来见见大家
I already told you, if it comes to a fight, I won't stand against the Volturi.
我告诉过你了 如果打了起来 我不会和沃统一作对的
It won't come to a fight.
不会打起来的
I'll be in the attic.
我在阁楼里
He's not a people person.
他不是个善于交际的人
We opened our home to 18 vampires.
我们向18个吸血鬼敞开了家门
Many with gifts of their own.
许多都有自己独特的天赋
Zafrina had power over the mind.
扎弗里那有控制思想的能力
She could make anyone see what she wanted them to.
她可以让任何人看到她想让其看到的东西
If she weren't holding my hand right now, I could swear this was real.
要不是她现在拉着我的手 我发誓这就是真的
I don't see anything.
我啥都没看见
Edward, you didn't tell me your wife is a shield.
爱德华 你没和我说过你老婆是个"盾牌"啊
What's a shield?
什么是"盾牌"?
The ones I've met are so different.
那些我见过的很不一样的人
It's a defensive talent.
这是一种防御技能
It's why I couldn't read your mind, even before.
这就是我之前看不透你的想法的原因
It's why Aro couldn't.
也是阿罗看不透的原因
You have a very powerful gift.
你有一个非常强大的技能
Oh, yeah, she's a shield, all right.
好吧 她是个"盾牌"
Shoulda put her on her ass.
应该电他的屁股的
Or your voltage has been exaggerated.
要么就是你的电压能力被夸大了
Maybe it only works on the weak.
也许它只对弱者有用
Garrett, I wouldn't.
盖里特 是我就不碰它
You are an amazing woman.
你真是个碉堡的女人
Now, you guys can do some serious damage.
现在 你们可以搞严重的破坏了
Which is why you'll need to control your phasing.
这就是你们要控制自己形态的原因
If your mom pisses you off, you don't want to tear her head off.
如果你妈惹怒你了 可别把她撕成碎片
Whoever's coming wasn't invited.
来者不善
Whoopa!
哈哈!
Vladimir, Stefan,
弗拉基米尔 史迪梵
you're a long way from home.
你们离家可够远的呀
What are they doing here?
他们在这儿干什么?
We heard the Volturi were moving against you.
我们听说沃统一家族正向你们逼来
But that you would not stand alone.
但你不会孤军奋战
We didn't do what we were accused of.
我们没犯被指控的罪行
We do not care what you did, Carlisle.
我不介意你做的什么 卡莱尔
We have been waiting a millennium
我们等了一千年了
for the Italian scum to be challenged.
等着那意大利混蛋受到挑战
It's not our plan to fight the Volturi.
我们没计划和沃统一打仗
Shame.
可惜
Aro's witnesses will be so disappointed.
阿罗的证人会很失望的
They enjoy a good fight.
他们喜欢看打仗
Aro's witnesses?
阿罗的证人?
Aww.
对
Still hoping they'll listen?
还在希望他们会听?
When Aro wants someone from a coven
当阿罗想从一群吸血鬼里得到某个人时
it's never long before evidence turns up proving that coven committed some crime.
不久之后就会有证据证明这群人犯了某个重罪
So he's done this before?
他原来干过这种事?
It happens so rarely, I never realized it was a pattern.
不常发生 我从没意识到这成了一个模式
Apparently he always pardons one person whose thoughts he claims are repentant.
显然他总是饶恕那个他声称悔罪态度良好的人
This person always has an ability.
这个人总是有某种能力
And they're always given a place with the Guard.
并且他们最后总会归入护卫军
This is all about Alice.
他是为爱丽丝而来
- He has no one like her.  - Which is why she left.
- 他没有她那样的人  - 这也是爱丽丝离开的原因
Why does he need witnesses?
为什么他需要证人?
To spread the word that justice has been served.
在他屠杀了整个族群后
after he slaughters an entire coven.
去广播正义得到伸张的消息
Benjamin, Tia,
本杰明 提亚
- we're leaving.  - And where will you go?
- 我们要走了  - 你们去哪儿?
What makes you think they'll be satisfied with Alice?
你凭什么认为他得到爱丽丝就满意了
What's to stop them from going after Benjamin next?
要是他接下来要本杰明 如何阻止?
Or Zafrina or Kate
或者扎弗里那 或者凯特
or anyone else with a gift? Anyone they want.
或者所有拥有技能的人?他们想要的任何人
Their goal isn't punishment, it's power.
他们的目的不是惩罚 而是权力
It's acquisition.
这是一种攫取
Carlisle might not ask you to fight, but I will.
卡莱尔或许不求你们战斗 但是我会
For the sake of my family. But also for yours.
为了我的家庭 也为了你们
And for the way you want to live.
为了我们生存的方式
The packs will fight.
狼族会加入战斗
We've never been afraid of vampires.
我们从没怕过吸血鬼
We will fight.
我们会战斗
This won't be the first time I fought a king's rule.
这不是我第一次挑战王权
We'll join you.
我们加入
No.
不
I will do the right thing, Amun.
我能把事做好
You may do as you please.
你请自便
We will stand with you.
我站在你们一边
So will we.
我们也是
That didn't take much.
也没多少人啊
Let's hope it doesn't come to that.
希望走不到那一步
We'll see.
拭目以待
Everyone showed courage.
每个人都展现了勇气
Though we knew that Aro's army was moving against us.
虽然我们知道阿罗的军队正向我们逼来
Soon we would face the dark gifts of Jane.
不久 我们就会要面对简的黑色法术了
And worse, the paralyzing vapor of her brother Alec
更恐怖的是阿莱克的麻痹蒸汽
who could rob you of sight, sound and touch.
它可以让你失去视觉 听觉和触觉
I refused him!
我拒绝了他!
I'm not with Carlisle!
我和卡莱尔不是一伙的!
Alec?
阿莱克?
I will never go against you.
我永远不会反对你
Of course not,
当然不会
my dear Toshiro.
我亲爱的秃屎罗
It seems Carlisle is still expecting you.
看起来卡莱尔还在期待你的加入
Carlisle is all but ensuring his own destruction.
卡莱尔只是在加速自己的毁灭
Sad,
悲哀啊
isn't it?
不是吗?
Aro will want us incapacitated before he attacks.
阿罗想在攻击之前就让我们丧失能力
Jane and Alec will try and take me out first because I can anticipate their moves.
简和阿莱克会想先把我干掉因为我能预测他们的行动
Too bad we don't all have your shield.
糟糕的是我们不是都有你的"盾牌"
Doesn't help me fight, though.
对我战斗没什么帮助
No, but you could help the rest of us,
但是你可以帮助其他人
if you could project it.
如果你能发射它
What do you mean?
你什么意思?
I mean shield someone other than yourself.
你可以保护除你之外的其他人
Is that possible?
这可能吗?
Gifts can be developed. Over time.
随着时间流逝 技能是可以点的
At first, mine was just in my palms.
起初 我的电压只能从手掌发射
Now I can radiate it all over my body.
现在我可以全身辐射
How do you do it?
你是怎么做到的?
- Tell me.  - Ow.
- 告诉我  - 疼
You need to visualize it.
你需要图像化盾牌
See how it moves.
看清它如何运动
What color it is.
什么颜色
Now picture it expanding.
然后想想它的扩展
Will it to go beyond you.
用意念驱使它脱离你的身体
I think she needs something to motivate her.
我觉得她需要一些激励她的东西
- No.  - It's all right, I can take it.
- 不  - 没事 我受得了
He says that now.
现在这么说
Focus, Bella, or he's gonna be hurting.
集中精神 贝拉 要不然他会很痛的
Edward, I'm not ready to do this yet.
爱德华 我还没准备好这样做
I'm sorry. I said that I wasn't ready.
抱歉 我刚说我没准备好了
Dude, you're not motivating her.
伙计 你不是在激励她
You want to try?
你想试试?
Kate!
凯特!
You seem to lack incentive.
看来激励不够
Shall I go see if Renesmee's awake?
用我去看看蕾埃斯梅醒了吗?
Are you crazy?
你疯了?
All right.
好
This one's on full power.
这次我用十成功力
It's painful, but it's bearable.
很疼 但是可以忍受
Okay, we should go again.
好了 再来一次
Emmett.
艾美特
I'm good.
我很好
"There's sweet music here that"
悠扬的音乐
"softer falls than petals from blown roses on the grass."
比草坪上的玫瑰花瓣更要轻盈
"Or night dews on still waters between walls"
比花岗岩院墙之间闪闪发光的小路上
"of shadowy granite in a gleaming pass."
静止的露珠更加柔然
"Music that brings sweet sleep down from the blissful skies."
音乐在喜悦的天空下带给人们甜美的梦
Mom.
妈妈
Hmm?
怎么了?
Did Aunt Alice and Uncle Jasper run away
爱丽丝阿姨和贾斯伯离开
because we're gonna die?
是因为我们要死了吗?
No.
不是
I think they left to keep us safer.
我觉得他们离开是为了让我们更安全
That's what all these other people are here for, too.
这也是所有其他人在这里的原因
I'll never let anybody hurt you.
我不会让任何人伤害你
Come here. Go to sleep.
到这儿来 睡吧
It's strange.
真奇怪
Physically, I feel like I could demolish a tank.
身体上 我感觉能摧毁一辆坦克
Mentally, I just feel drained.
精神上 我感到精疲力尽
How about a bath?
洗个澡?
I do remember how to undress myself.
我还记得怎么宽衣解带
Yeah, I just do it so much better.
是 我只是脱得更专业
Bella,
贝拉
I've had a bad habit of underestimating you.
我有一个小看你的不好的习惯
Every obstacle you've faced,
你面对的每一个障碍
I'd think you couldn't overcome it.
我都觉得你克服不了
And you just did.
但你还是克服了
You're the reason they have something to fight for.
他们他们战斗的动力
My family.
还有我的我家人
I'm gonna get the water running.
我去把水放上
Alice made sure only I would get the message.
爱丽丝确定只有我得到了这个信息
Because only my mind would be safe from Aro.
因为只有我的思想阿罗是看不透的
I'm surprised you took a break from Jedi training.
我很惊奇你在魔鬼训练时抽空休息
If I don't take Renesmee to my dad, he'll come to us.
我如果不带蕾埃斯梅去找我爸 他会来找我的
27 vampires, one human.
27个吸血鬼 一个人类
Not so great.
不太好
I know that's what you told Edward.
我知道你对爱德华撒了谎
Whatever.
随便
I'm just glad to get away from all those reeking bloodsuckers.
我只是很高兴能远离那些臭烘烘的吸血鬼
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I know.
我知道
They're the good guys.
他们是好吸血鬼
But come on,
但是你想想
Dracula One and Two are
罗马尼亚那两个吸血鬼（很像同性恋的那两个重口音吸血鬼）
creepy.
很吓人
There she is. Come here.
他来了 到这儿来
Oh!
哦!
Wow! Look at you.
哇 看看你
You've grown half a foot!
已经半英尺了!
Seriously.
真的
Like 6 inches.
得有6英寸
Come on inside. Lunch is on the table.
进来吧 午饭好了
We got a tree to decorate, huh?
还得装饰圣诞树
I've actually got a few errands to run, guys.
我还有点事要办 各位
I'll be back soon, okay?
一会儿就回来 好吗?
Come on. Let's go.
我们走
Alice's note gave me a new sense of hope.
爱丽丝的留言给了我新的希望
Maybe she had a plan for us after all.
也许她给我们准备了计划
And maybe J. Jenks was the key.
也许J·金肯斯是问题的关键
- I'm meeting Mr. Jenks.  - Right this way.
- 我想见金肯斯  - 这边走
- Mrs. Cullen.  - Hi.
- 库仑夫人  - 你好
I'm so happy you called.
很高兴你能来电话
I always meet my private clients here.
我总是在这儿见我的私人客户
It's more comfortable than the office.
这儿比办公室更舒服
And it's more public.
这里更加公开
Ah.
啊
What type of work do you do, J.?
你做什么工作的?
Oh, you know, this and that.
这这那那的
It's always different, which keeps it interesting.
经常换 这样才有意思
Have you known Alice and Jasper long?
你认识爱丽丝和贾斯伯的时间长吗?
I've been working with them for more than 20 years.
我已经和他们一起工作20多年了
And my late partner knew Jasper 15 years before that.
我最近的伴侣在那之前15年就认识他了
He is, uh,
他
unusually well-preserved.
不同寻常的活的很好
Yes, he is.
是的
I trust that Mr. Jasper is enjoying his vacation.
我相信贾斯伯先生旅行很愉快
He didn't tell you where he was going, did he?
他没告诉你他去哪儿?
No, no, no, he just mentioned that he was leaving
没有 他只是在过来下达命令时
when he came by to place his order.
提到了他要走
I assume that his order is ready?
我猜他的要求你已经准备好了?
Of course.
当然
I've never been late with a delivery.
我从没交货迟到过
There a problem?
有问题?
No.
没有
My husband and I thought that we'd all be traveling together.
我丈夫和我觉得我们会和他们一起旅行的
Jasper said only two were traveling.
贾斯伯说只要两个要履行
His instructions were very clear.
他的指示很明确
It's my mistake.
我的错
Apparently, that's not going to happen.
显然 这种事不会发生
Alice's vision was clear.
爱丽丝的预见很明确
Renesmee would have a future.
蕾埃斯梅会有一个未来
But Edward and I wouldn't be a part of it.
但是爱德华不会成为其中的一部分
How ya doing?
你好吗?
"My dearest Renesmee,"
"我最亲爱的蕾埃斯梅"
"I thought we would have forever together."
"我原以为我们会永远在一起"
"But forever isn't as long as I'd hoped."
"但是永远并不像我预期的那样长"
"I know now why Alice left me clues."
"我现在知道为什么爱丽丝给我留下线索"
"It was to keep you safe."
"这是为了你的安全"
"Everything you and Jacob will need is in this pack."
"你和雅各布需要的所有东西都在这个包里"
"Jacob will protect you."
"雅各布会保护你的"
"And he'll help you learn about the Ticuna legends."
"而且他会帮你学习部落的传奇故事"
It's a romantic notion, isn't it?
很浪漫的打算 不是吗?
That a righteous few can defy a great evil.
少数正义的人可以战胜强大的邪恶力量
I must admit, you even had me believing.
我必须承认 你甚至让我也相信了
For a moment.
一瞬间
Well, good luck. You're gonna need it.
祝你好运 你会需要好运的
Cheers.
笑一个
The snow is sticking.
雪要覆盖地面了
Hey, we still have today.
我们还拥有今天
I'm so glad Charlie found somebody to take care of him.
真高兴卡莱尔找到一个能关心他的人
Bella, no one's giving up here.
贝拉 没人会放弃的
All right! Present time! Let's go!
好了! 拆礼物了! 走吧
Seth, Leah, stop eating.
赛斯 里亚 别吃了
Jake, you start. Get it going.
雅各布 你先拆
- What did you get me?  - I'm not giving you anything.
- 你送给我的是什么?  - 我啥都没准备
Hey! No, come on, what did you get me?
嘿! 得了 你到底送我什么?
Well, Dad, we didn't have time to wrap yours,
爸 我们没时间包装你的礼物
but here it is.
给你
It's a 5-day fishing trip to Fraser River.
这是菲莎河5日钓鱼游
It's for you and Sue.
给你和苏准备的
You leave tomorrow.
明天出发
Wow, that's really nice. Thank you.
哇 真不错 谢谢
Tomorrow? I can't leave tomorrow.
明天?我明天不能走
I made arrangements for you at work.
我替你把工作安排好了
Sneaky.
真狡猾
And extravagant.
奢侈
And non-refundable, I'm afraid.
恐怕还是不能退款
You two trying to get rid of me?
你们两个想把我赶走?
Because it's working!
你们成功了?
Fraser River. That means we'll be chasing Cutthroat.
菲莎河 那我们就能捕切喉鳟了
We might even hook a Rainbow or some Bulls.
甚至能钓到彩虹鱼和公牛鱼
Woman knows her trout.
这女人很了解
Hey, beautiful. Let me see.
嘿 美女 让我看看
Jacob make this for you?
雅各布给你做的?
Wanna put it on?
想带上吗?
It's so pretty.
真漂亮
It is really pretty.
真心漂亮
That's what I'm talkin' about.
就是要这个
A little pre-battle bonfire.
大战之前的篝火
Telling war stories.
讲战斗故事
Or just standing there like frickin' statues.
或者只是站那儿 想他妈的雕像
Name any American battle. I was there.
随便说个美国战役 我都参加过
Little Bighorn.
小比格霍恩河战役（1876年）
I came this close to biting Custer.
差一点就咬到了卡斯特（美国将军）
But the Indians got him first.
但是印第安人先把他干掉了
Try Oleg's assault on Constantinople.
说说奥列格攻打君士坦丁堡战役
He didn't win that one on his own.
他不是靠自己的力量赢的
If you're talking battles,
如果你们要谈战争
you're talking the Eleven Years' War.
谈谈爱尔兰联盟战争吧（1641–1653）
No one does rebellion like the Irish.
没人像爱尔兰人一样反叛
You lost the Eleven Years' War.
你们打输了
Aye. But it was one hell of a rebellion.
对 但却是一场轰轰烈烈的叛逆
When we ruled, everything came to us.
当我们掌权时 所有东西都是我们的
Prey,
猎物
diplomats,
外交官
favor seekers.
赞成者
Such was our power.
这是我们的权利
But we never put on white hats and called ourselves saints.
但我们从没有带上白帽子说自己是圣人
We were honest about what we were.
我们对自己是什么很诚实
We sat still for a very long time.
我们停滞不前了很长时间
We didn't notice we were beginning to petrify.
我们并没有意识到自己走向僵化刻板
Perhaps the Volturi did us a favor when they
也许沃统一家族在他们烧掉我们城堡时帮了
burned our castles.
帮了我们的忙
We've been waiting 1,500 years
我们为了复仇
to return that favor.
已经等了1500年了
We have been ready to do battle for ages.
我们已经准备好长期作战
I can't help thinking,
我禁不住去想
all these people are putting themselves in danger
所有人都置身危险
because I fell in love with a human.
只因我爱上了一个人类
You found your mate.
你找到了伴侣
You deserve to be happy.
你应该高兴
But at what cost?
但代价呢?
Everyone here has something to fight for.
在这儿的每个人都有战斗的原因
I certainly do.
我当然也有
Carlisle, I've never thanked you.
卡莱尔 我从没感谢过你
For this extraordinary life.
谢谢你给我这个不同寻常的生活
This means "More than my own life."
这个意思是"胜于自己的生命"
That's how much I love you.
我就是这么爱你
Tomorrow I'm gonna need you to stay with Jacob.
明天我要你和雅各布在一起
No matter what.
不管发生了什么
Even if I tell him that...
甚至我让他...
That he has to take you somewhere.
带你去别的地方
Hey.
嘿
Baby, it's all right.
宝贝 没事儿的
You're gonna be safe.
你会安全的
Always.
你总会很安全
If we live through this,
我们我们逃过这一劫
I'll follow you anywhere, woman.
我愿追随你到天涯海角 美女
Now you tell me.
现在你才说
The Redcoats are coming! The Redcoats are coming!
红衣服们来了! 红衣服们来了!
Aro's looking for Alice.
阿罗在找爱丽丝
Aro,
阿罗
let us discuss things as we used to.
让我们像以前一样谈点东西
In a civilized manner.
和和气气地谈
Fair words, Carlisle.
说的挺好 卡莱尔
But a little out of place,
但是有点不合适吧
given the battalion you've assembled against us.
鉴于你集合军队对抗我们
I can promise you, that was never my intent.
我向你保证 那不是我的意图
No laws have been broken.
你们已经违反了法令
We see the child.
我们看到那孩子了
Do not treat us as fools.
别把我们当猴耍
She is not an Immortal!
她不是吸血鬼孩子
These witnesses can attest to that.
这些证人可以证明
Or you can look.
你也可以自己看
See the flush of human blood in her cheeks.
看她脸上人血流动的红晕
Artifice!
伪装!
I will collect every facet of the truth.
我会弄清楚真相的每个方面
But from someone more central to the story.
但得从这个故事的主角那
Edward,
爱德华
as the child clings to your newborn mate,
既然这孩子依恋你新生的妻子
I assume you are involved.
我想你得过来
I'd like to meet her.
我想见见她
Ah.
啊
Young Bella.
年轻的贝拉
Immortality becomes you.
你已经永生了
Ah...I hear her strange heart.
啊...我听到他奇怪的心跳了
Hello, Aro.
你好 阿罗
Magnifico!
碉堡了!
Half mortal,
半人
half immortal.
半吸血鬼
Conceived and carried by this newborn
在她还仍是人类的时候
while she was still human.
被这个新生者孕育
Impossible!
不可能!
Do you think they fooled me, brother?
那你觉得他们把我耍了 弟弟?
Bring the informer forward.
把报信者带上来
Is that the child you saw?
那是你看到的孩子吗?
I'm not sure.
我不确定
Jane.
简
She's changed. This child is bigger.
她变了 这个孩子更大了
Then your allegations were false.
所以你的陈述是假的
The Cullens are innocent.
库仑家族是无辜的
I take full responsibility for my mistake.
我对我的错误付全部责任
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Caius, no!
盖伊思 不要!
Irina!
伊琳娜!
Blind them.
让他们看不见
Give me my sight back.
把我的视力还回来
Tanya, this is what they want.
坦尼亚 这就是他们想要的
If you attack now, we'll all die.
如果你进攻 我们都会死
Pain.
痛
It's working.
有用
Aro, you see there's no law broken here.
阿罗 你已经看到没有法令被违反
Agreed.
同意
But does it then follow
但这能表示
that there is no danger?
这没有危险吗?
For the first time in our history
我们历史上第一次
humans pose a threat
人类对我们
to our kind.
形成了威胁
Their modern technology
他们的现代科技
has given birth to weapons that could destroy us.
制造出了可以毁灭我们的武器
Maintaining our secret
保守我们的秘密
has never been more imperative.
从没像这么急迫
In such perilous times,
在这个危险的时代
only the known
只有已知的
is safe.
才是安全的
Only the known
只有已知的
is tolerable.
才是可以容忍的
And we know nothing
而我们对这个孩子
of what this child will become.
会变成什么样子一无所知
Can we live with such uncertainty?
我们能忍受这样的未知吗?
Spare ourselves a fight today,
今天不打
only to die
死期就在
tomorrow.
明天
No.
不
Alice.
爱丽丝
Alice!
爱丽丝!
My dear, dear Alice,
我亲爱的爱丽丝
we're so glad to see you here, after all.
真高兴最终能在这儿见到你
I have evidence the child won't be a risk to our kind.
我有证据证明这个孩子不会对我们的族群造成威胁
Let me show you.
让我展示给你
Brother?
哥哥?
It doesn't matter what I show you.
你看到了什么不重要
Even when you see.
就算你知道了
You still won't change your decision.
你仍不会改变你的决定
Now!
趁现在!
Take care of my daughter.
照顾好我女儿
Get them.
把他们抓回来
Hmm!
喝!
Take her away.
把她带走
Let her go!
放她走!
Jacob!
雅各布!
Watch out!
当心!
Bitch!
臭婊子
Finally.
终于
Now you know.
现在你知道了
That's your future.
那就是你的将来
Unless you decide on another course.
除非你做出不同的决定
We cannot alter our course. The child still poses a grave threat.
我们不能改主意 这孩子对我们有致命威胁
But what if you were sure she could
但如果你能确定她可以
remain concealed from the human world?
在人类世界中隐藏起来呢?
Could we leave in peace?
我们能安然离开吗?
Of course. But that cannot be known.
当然 但我们不可能知道
Actually, it can.
实际上 我们知道
I've been searching for witnesses of my own
我一直在巴西的Ticuna部落
among the Ticuna tribes of Brazil.
自己找寻证人
- We have enough witnesses.  - Let him speak, brother.
- 我们有足够的证人  - 让她说 弟弟
I am half human,
我是半人
half vampire.
半吸血鬼
Like the Child.
和那孩子一样
A vampire seduced my mother,
一个吸血鬼勾引了我的妈妈
who died giving birth to me.
她在生我的时候死去
My aunt Huilen
我阿姨慧轮
raised me as her own.
把我当亲儿子养大
I made her immortal.
我让她永生
How old are you?
你多大了?
150 years.
150岁
At what age did you reach maturity?
你几岁达到成熟?
I became full-grown seven years after my birth.
我在出生后的第七年生长完成
I have not changed since then.
从那之后我就没变过
And your diet?
你吃什么?
Blood,
血
human food.
人类食物
I can survive on either.
吃哪个都能活
These children are much like us.
这种孩子跟我们很像
Regardless, the Cullens have been consorting with werewolves.
不管这个 库仑家族和狼人交往
Our natural enemies.
我们永恒的敌人
Dear ones,
亲爱的各位
there is no danger here.
这里没有危险
We will not fight
我们不打仗
today.
在今天
Such a prize.
算你们走运
We have them on the run. Now is the time to attack.
我们击退他们了 趁现在进攻吧
Not today.
今天不打
You're all fools!
你们都二啊!
The Volturi might be gone.
沃统一家族或许走了
But they will never forgive
但他们永远不会原谅
what happened here.
这里发生的一切
You have a beautiful family.
你的家人真好看
She's gonna be around for a long time, isn't she?
他会在身边很长时间的
A very long time.
非常长
I'm glad she has you.
很高兴她能拥有你
So should I start calling you "Dad"?
我应该开始叫你"爸"吗?
No.
不
Hey.
呵
嘿
Yeah. We're all gonna be together now.
对 我们都会在一起
I wanna show you something.
我想给你看个东西
What?
什么?
I'm Edward Cullen.
我是爱德华·库仑
How did you do that?
你怎么做到的?
Been practicing.
练出来的
Now you know.
现在你知道了
Nobody's ever loved anybody as much as I love you.
没人曾向我这样爱你这么深
There's one exception.
有一个例外
Will you show me again?
能再给我看看吗?
We've got a lotta time.
我们有的是时间
Forever.
到永远